Kinesiology Department. Class schedules and enrollment statistics. 1920-1977.
UCLA Library Special Collections
Kinesiology Department. Class schedules and enrollment statistics.
1920-1977
University Archives Record Series 332
UCLA Library Special Collections
0.6 linear ft. (2 boxes)
Record Series 332 contains class schedules and enrollment statistics generated by UCLA's Kinesiology Department between 1920 and 1977.
University of California, Los Angeles. Kinesiology Department.
Access
COLLECTION STORED OFF-SITE AT SRLF: Open for research. Advance notice required for access. Contact the UCLA Library Special Collections Reference Desk for paging information.
Historical note
The Department of Kinesiology trace its origins to the Department of Physical Education, which was established in 1915 as part of the Los Angeles State Normal School. In 1919 the department became part of the Teachers College of the Southern Branch, with separate departments for men and women. During the 1920s, the department's efforts were devoted to the training of Physical Education teachers and the administration of the Physical Education classes that were required of all undergraduates. In 1932 the Men's and Women's Gymnasiums were completed. In 1938 the M.S. degree in Physical Education was authorized. In 1939 the department became part of the newly established College of Applied Arts. In 1952 separate divisions for men and women were eliminated. In 1960 the College of Applied Arts was dissolved and replaced by the College of Fine Arts. The Physical Education Department was then transferred to the College of Letters and Science, Division of Life Sciences. In 1962 the revised physical education major was approved and focused on Kinesiology (the science of human movement) and one of three allied fields: physiology, psychology, or sociology. In 1973 the department changed its name to Kinesiology. When Donald T. Hardy retired in 1976, he was recognized as the founding father of the Kinesiology department. The department first offered a Ph.D. degree in Kinesiology in 1979. In 1990 the Kinesiology Department changed its name to the Physiological Sciences Department.
Scope and Content
Record Series 332 contains class schedules and enrollment statistics generated by UCLA's Kinesiology Department between 1920 and 1977. The bulk of this record series focuses on Summer Sessions. Files include schedules, statistics, correspondence, and other materials that contributed to the organization of schedules.
This is an inactive record series; no additional University records are expected to be added.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 3466857
- Class schedules., 1963-1972. (Box 1, Folders 1-9)
- Enrollment., 1962-1969. (Box 1, Folders 10-16)
- Summer Session enrollment., 1963-1976. (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Record of teaching personnel during Summer Session., 1953-1976. (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Summer Session - correspondence., 1920-1921. (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Summer Session - class schedule, correspondence., 1925. (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Summer Session - news clippings., 1925. (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Summer Session - schedule, correspondence., 1962. (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Summer Session - schedule, correspondence, staff listing., 1963. (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Summer Session - schedule, correspondence., 1964. (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Summer Session - staff listing, correspondence., 1965. (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Summer Session - schedule, correspondence., 1966. (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Summer Session - schedule, correspondence., 1967. (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Summer Session - correspondence., 1968. (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Summer Session - enrollment data, correspondence., 1969. (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Summer Session - course outlines, correspondence., 1970. (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Summer Session - schedule, correspondence., 1971. (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Summer Session - schedule, correspondence., 1972. (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Enrollments., 1929-1940. (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Summer Session - correspondence., 1973. (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Summer Session - schedule, correspondence., 1974. (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Summer Session - schedule, correspondence., 1975. (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Summer Session - schedule, correspondence., 1976. (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Summer Session - schedule, correspondence., 1977. (Box 2, Folder 6)